Preliminary Inventory of the David Nelson Rowe papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Chinese Communist Affairs: A Bi-monthly Review, vols. 2-6, 1965-1969 (Box 56)
- Course readings, 1961 (Box 57)
- Cooperation Between the Republic of China and African Countries, draft, 1963 February (Box 57)
- Committee of One Million Against the Admission of Communist China into the United Nations, 1964 (Box 57)
- Correspondence, 1956 (Box 57)
- General correspondence, 1957-1964 (Box 58)
- "Thai Irredentism and French Indochina: A Study of a Controversial Aspect of Thai Nationalism," student dissertation, 1962 (Box 58)
- Free Afro-Asia: Cooperation Between the Republic of China and African Countries, draft, 1963 (Box 58)
- Maps of Mozambique, undated (Box 58)
- Communism in China, 1961-1966 (Box 59)
- International studies, 1970 (Box 59)
- Mozambique, 1963 (Box 59)
- Yale University, correspondence, 1970 (Box 60)
- Invitation to Nixon inauguration, 1969 (Box 60)
- Map of countries in Pacific and Bay of Bengal, undated (Box 60)
- Early course materials and writings, 1938 (Box 61)
- Early course materials and writings, 1927-1942 (Box 62)
- Correspondence, 1938-1940 (Box 63)
- Photographs of Peking palaces, undated (Box 64)
- Japanese propaganda postcards, late 1930s (Box 64)
- Small Japanese propaganda posters and leaflets, circa 1937 (Box 64)
- Photographs depicting scenes of Sino-Japanese conflict, circa 1937 (Box 64)
- Political science course materials, 1968-1974 (Box-folder 65: 1-4)
- American Committee in Aid of Chinese Industrial Cooperatives (Indusco), 1942-1943 (Box 65)
  - Bulletins, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 65: 5)
  - Constitution and by-laws, circa 1942 (Box-folder 65: 6)
  - Memoranda and minutes of the Executive Board, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 65: 7)
  - Correspondence, China, 1942 (Box-folder 65: 8)
  - Finance statements, 1943 (Box-folder 65: 9)
  - Field committee, 1943 (Box-folder 65: 10)
  - News bulletins from China, 1942 (Box-folder 65: 11)
  - United China Relief, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 65: 12)
  - Washington Indusco, 1942 (Box-folder 65: 13)
  - Philippines, correspondence, 1940 (Box-folder 65: 14)
  - China Aid Council, Child Care and Development Committee, 1942 (Box-folder 65: 15)
- Political science course materials, 1972-1974 (Box 66)
- Scholars for Nixon-Agnew campaign materials, 1968 (Box 67)
- U.S policy toward Asia, 1966 (Box 67)
- Report to Congress by President Nixon, 1971 February (Box 67)
- Personal papers of Matthew and Elizabeth Holmes given to Rowe for research, 1861 (Box 67)
  Includes journal, bank slips, and other materials in Chinese relating to trade in China.
- Albums of photographs depicting life of missionaries in China, street scenes, and architecture, 1915-1920s (Box 68)
- Materials relating to symposium at Emory University, 1957 (Box 69)
- Cooperation Between the Republic of China and African Countries, drafts and research materials, 1962 (Box 69)
- Biography of George C. Marshall, correspondence and notes, 1963 (Box 70)
- "Informal 'Diplomatic Relations:' The Case of Japan and the Republic of China," writings, 1972-1974 (Box 70)
- Transcript from seminar, 1974 March (Box 70)
- Lectures at U.S. Naval War College, 1958 (Box 71)
- Political science course materials, 1974 (Box 71)
- Printed matter, 1922-1973 (Box 71)
- Chinese farmers in Liberia, photographs, 1962 (Box 72)
- Minutes from the Conference on the Limitation of Armament, 1922 (Box 72)
- Air War College, 1961 (Box 73)
- India, Afghanistan, and Iran printed matter (Box 73)
- Lecture materials, 1959-1964 (Box 73)
- U.S. Army War College, course and lecture materials, 1959-1961 (Box 74)
- Account books and vouchers from Taiwan trip, 1959 (Box 75)
- Red China lobby project, 1968 (Box 75)
- Correspondence, 1945-1962 (Box 75)
- Photographs from Rhodesia, undated (Box 76)
- Arizona trip, 1971 (Box 76)
- Conference materials, 1957 (Box 76)
- Council on International Relations, 1957-1965 (Box 77)
- National Council of Scholars, finances, 1969-1971 (Box 77)
- Nixon presidential campaign, 1968 (Box 77)
- Harold D. Lasswell, World Politics Faces Economics, 1945 (Box 78)
- Notebooks of minutes from meetings, 1959 (Box 78)
- Handwritten transcripts from meetings, 1958 (Box 79)
  In Chinese, with handwritten English translations.
- Obituary of George C. Marshall from New York Times, 1959 (Box 79)
- Handwritten transcripts from meetings, 1959 (Box 80)
  In Chinese, with English translations.
- University Professors for Academic Order, correspondence and newsletters, 1971-1972 (Box 81)
- Booklets on Sino-African technical cooperation, 1966-1969 (Box 81)
- Conference materials, 1973-1974 (Box 81)
- Yale University, Department of Political Science, memoranda, 1971-1972 (Box 82)
- Lists of newly independent countries in Africa and Asia, 1960s (Box 82)
- Anthony Trawick Bouscaren, manuscript and related correspondence, 1966 (Box 82)
- U.S. House of Representatives, Foreign Affairs Committee, Subcommittee on Asian and Pacific Affairs, 1972 May (Box 82)
- American Council for World Freedom, correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 82)
- Conference materials, 1970-1973 (Boxes 83-85)
  - Bound volume of World Anti-Communist League conference proceedings from the Philippines, 1971 (Box 83)
  - Anti-communist organizations, 1972-1973 (Box 83)
  - World Anti-Communist League, 1970-1973 (Box 84)
  - Photographs from the eighth conference of Asian Peoples' Anti-Communist League, 1970s (Box 84)
  - Sound recording, "Let's Join Our Hands, Friends of the Earth," children's song, undated (Box 85)
    1 vinyl 7-inch disc.
  - Anti-communist organizations, 1970-1972 (Box 85)
- Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 86)
- Personal file from military service, 1963-1964 (Box 87)
- Travel documents, 1956 (Box 87)
- Yale University, 1967-1968 (Box 87)
- Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 88)
- James Daniel Theberge, The Soviet Presence in Latin America, New York, published by Crane, Russak [for] National Strategy Information Center, 1974 (Box 89)
- Political science course materials, 1974 (Box 89)
- Soil map of Swaziland, undated (Box 89)
- Agriculture in Asia, printed matter, 1969-1973 (Box 90)
- David Nelson Rowe, Modern China: A Brief History, Princeton, N.J.: Van Nostrand, 1959 (Box 90)
- Comments and Proposed Amendments Concerning the Dumbarton Oaks Proposals, submitted by the delegations to the United Nations Conference on International Organization, 1945 May 7 (Box 91)
- Correspondence, 1960-1970 (Box 91)
- Agriculture and farmers associations in Taiwan, 1956 (Box 92)
- Asian Peoples Anti-Communist League, conference materials, 1963-1964 (Box 92)
- News bulletins regarding China and the United Nations, 1965 (Box 92)
- Biographies, undated (Box 92)
- Modern China, drafts, circa 1959 (Box 93)
- Modern China, drafts, circa 1959 (Box 94)
- China News, 1958 January 2-May 31 (Box 95)
- Chinese Agricultural Technical Mission to Vietnam, reports, 1965-1966 (Box 95)
- Contracts between Electricity of Vietnam and Taiwan Power Company, 1965-1966 (Box 95)
- Travel documents, 1968-1970 (Box 96)
- Sino-Japanese relations study, 1950s (Box 97)
- Peter R. Moody, correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 97)
- Chinese technical cooperation in Chile and Brazil, 1968 (Box 98)
- Sino-African technical cooperation file, 1971 (Box 98)
- Photocopy of clippings on Yalta Conference, 1955 (Box 98)
- Swaziland Ministry of Agriculture, bulletins, 1968 (Box 98)
- Certificates and invitations, 1946-1961 (Box 98)
- Chinese technical cooperation and agriculture project in Latin America, weekly reports, 1966-1967 (Box 99)
- Chinese technical cooperation mission in Mexico and the Dominican Republic, 1965-1966 (Box 100)
- Personal correspondence, 1967-1971 (Box 101)
- Chinese technical cooperation mission, 1965-1968 (Box 101)
- Sino-African technical cooperation file, 1968 (Box 102)
- "1950 People's Yearbook," draft (Box 103)
- Sino-African technical cooperation file, 1968 (Box 103)
- Third Sino-Thai Ministerial Conference on Economic Cooperation, Taipei, printed matter, 1970 (Box 103)
- Information bulletins for Yale students, 1964-1965 (Box 104)
- American Afro-Asian Educational Exchange, fellowship application submissions, 1965 (Box 104)
- Photographs of Rowe in Seoul, South Korea, 1965 (Box 104)
- Freedom Center, Seoul, 1964 (Box 104)
- Yale University, correspondence, 1966 (Box 104)
- Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 105)
  Includes discussions of statements made by Ambassador Liu Chieh and Chiang Ching-kuo.
- Statement by Rowe before the Foreign Relations Committee of the U.S. Senate, 1966 March (Box 105)
- Freedom Center, Seoul, 1964-1965 (Box 105)
- Asian Peoples Anti-Communist League conference in the Philippines, photographs, 1961 May (Box 106)
- Yale University, International Relations Department, PhD exam and miscellaneous materials, 1961-1964 (Box 106)
- Asian Peoples Anti-Communist League and American Afro-Asian Educational Exchange youth project, 1965 (Box 107)
- Annual reports and schedules of the farming missions in Africa from the Sino-African Technical Cooperation Committee, 1967 (Box 107)
- "The Nixon China Policy and the Balance of Power,", 1973 April (Box 107)
- Photographs and brochures of ancient and early modern Chinese and Japanese art, undated (Boxes 108-109)
- World Anti-Communist League, conference materials and related correspondence, 1970 (Box 110)
- Receipts and travel documents, 1968 (Box 110)
- Miscellaneous, 1967 (Box 111)
- Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 112)
- Republican National Committee, Task Force on the Conduct of Foreign Relations, memoranda and correspondence, 1966 (Box 112)
- Chinese technical cooperation in Vietnam, 1965 (Box 113)
- Chinese technical cooperation in Rhodesia and the Ivory Coast, 1966-1971 (Box 114)
- World Youth Crusade for Freedom, 1966 (Box 115)
- China, the United Nations, and United States Policy, booklet, 1960s (Box 115)
- U.S. foreign policy, China, 1970 (Box 115)
- United Nations and China, 1967 (Box 115)
- Anti-communist groups, 1964 (Box 116)
- American Afro-Asian Educational Exchange, correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box 116)
- American Conservative Union, 1967 (Box 116)
- Westminster College Summer Institute, 1965-1966 (Box 116)
- Army War College, National Strategy seminar, 1963 (Box 116)
- General travel and lecture materials, 1965-1967 (Box 117)
- Marvin Liebman, correspondence, 1966 (Box 117)
- Committee of One Million Against the Admission of Communist China into the United Nations, printed matter and memoranda, 1966 (Box 117)
- International relations, 1966-1967 (Box 117)
- "The Chinese Communist Political System," speech at National War College, 1965 August 1 (Box 118)
- World Youth Crusade for Freedom, correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 118)
- U.S. foreign policy, Vietnam, 1966 (Box 118)
- Asian Peoples Anti-Communist League, reports from the tenth annual conference, 1964 (Box 118)
- Safari, 1964 (Box 118)
- U.S. foreign policy, Vietnam, 1965 (Box 119)
- Young Americans for Freedom, correspondence and printed matter, 1966 (Box 119)
- Alton Frye, Nazi Germany and the American Hemisphere, 1933-1941, New Haven: Yale University Press, 1967 (Box 119)
- China, foreign relations, 1964-1966 (Box 119)
- Notecards of collected quotations, organized by subject, 1930-1950s (Box 120)
- Relm Foundation, correspondence, 1964 (Box 121)
- Republican National Committee, Task Force on the Conduct of Foreign Relations, meeting materials, 1967 May (Box 121)
- National Strategy Seminar at Army War College materials, 1965 (Box 122)
- Stamps, 1965 (Box 122)
- Asian Peoples Anti-Communist League, conference materials, Seoul, South Korea, 1966 (Box 122)
- Republican National Committee, Task Force on the Conduct of Foreign Relations, meeting materials, 1965 (Box 123)
- Speaking engagements, 1959-1967 (Boxes 123-124)
- Yale University, social science degree committee materials, 1963-1969 (Box 124)
- Council on International Relations, minutes and correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 124)
- Sound recordings, 1956-1970 (Box 125)
  15 7-inch reels of 1/4-inch sound tape.
- Sound recordings, 1958-1967 (Box 126)
  13 7-inch reels of 1/4-inch sound tape.
- 1 microfilm reel, Index to Su-lien Yin-Mou Wen-cheng, edited by D. N. Rowe, 1960 (Box 126)
- Sound recordings, 1958, undated (Box 127)
  13 7-inch reels and 1 5-inch reel of 1/4-inch sound tape.
- Sound recordings, 1958 (Box 128)
- Sound recordings, "Dedication of Freedom Studies Center,", 1966 September 25 (Box 129)
  1 5-inch reel of 1/4-inch sound tape.
- Sound recordings, 1961-1967 (Box 129)
- Sound recordings, 1967-1977 (Box 130)
  14 audiocassette tapes.
- Army Reserve file, 1949-1954 (Box-folder 131: 1)
- Yale University, Strategic Intelligence Research and Analysis unit, 1949 (Box-folder 131: 2)
- Army Advisory Committee (Civil Defense for the New Haven Area), correspondence, 1947-1953 (Box-folder 131: 3)
- Army Advisory Committee, bulletins and pamphlets, 1947-1953 (Box-folder 131: 4)
- Military Intelligence ROTC program, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 131: 5)
- Report of the Education Exchange Survey to the Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers, Tokyo, 1949 September 17 (Box-folder 131: 6)
- Department of State, lecture by D. N. Rowe, Foreign Service instructor, "Analysis of Strategic Areas,", 1950-1951 (Box-folder 131: 7)
- National War College, correspondence and writings, 1948-1950 (Box-folder 131: 8)
- Yale University, 463rd Strategic Research and Analysis unit, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 131: 9)
- War Department, correspondence, 1944-1947 (Box-folder 131: 10)
- The China Manual, correspondence, 1954 (Box-folder 132: 1)
- The United Nations Conference on International Organization, San Francisco proceedings, 1945 June 1-15 (Box-folder 132: 2)
- Army War College, 1952 (Box-folder 132: 3)
- George Washington University, Human Resources Research Office, correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 132: 4)
- Leaders of Communist China, report, 1950 August (Box-folder 132: 5)
- The United Nations Conference on International Organization, San Francisco, 1945 April-May (Boxes 133-134)
  - Summary reports, 1945 (Box-folder 133: 1)
  - Session materials, 1945 (Box-folder 133: 2)
  - Proceedings and related materials, 1945 (Box-folder 133: 3-4)
  - Proceedings and related materials, 1945 (Box 134)
- Atlases of China prepared by the Central Intelligence Agency, 1950s (Box 135)
- Maps of China, 1960s (Box 135)
- National Council of Scholars, meeting materials, 1968-1970 (Box 136)
- National Council of Scholars, meeting materials and correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box 137)
- National Council of Scholars, correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box 138)
- Ross Y. Koen, The China Lobby in American Politics, New York: Macmillan, 1960 (Box 138)
- Land reform in China, 1954 (Box 138)
- Monographs, published and unpublished speeches and writings, 1927-1982 (Boxes 141-142)
- Visual materials, undated (Box 143)
  Includes some photographs, large format glass negatives, large format negatives, and 35 mm negatives, some of which depict the Taiping Rebellion and Japanese propaganda in China.
  Access
  Glass negatives may only be used under supervision.
- Illustrations of Taiping Rebellion, glass lantern slides, 1861-1971 (Box 143)
  May only be used under supervision.
- Japanese propaganda in China, 1937-1940s (Box 143)
  Consists of 35 mm slides depicting Japanese propaganda posters. See also: Box 1.
- Certificate of military service, 1952 (Box 143)
- American Diplomatic Service envelope, 1939 (Box 143)
  Addressed to Mr. Frank P. Lockhart, Jr. at Princeton University. Sealed with red wax seals of the Embassy of the United States of AMerican in China.
- Declassified U.S. government records, 1921-1922, 1941-1948 (Boxes 139-140, 144)
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Includes some interfield, unclassified government records. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover.
  - 2015 May release of records, 1921-1922 (Box 139)
    Consists of memoranda and correspondence prepared for American delegates to the Conference on Limitation of Armament, as well as a report on Japanese immigration to the United States, arranged by form and thereunder chronologically by date of creation.
  - 2016 January release of records, 1941-1945, 1948 (Boxes 140, 144)
    Consists of Council on Foreign Relations digests of discussions, memoranda, agendas, and lists (1941-1945), particularly from various study groups of the War and Peace Studies Project, as well as United States Information Service (USIS) correspondence and memoranda (1948), arranged by original folder title and thereunder chronologically by date of creation.